

■ asiya.shakeel78@yahoo.com

**** 9292313913

9 https://github.com/asiyashakeel78

EDUCATION

SUMMARY

Masters in Applied **Mathematics**

Experienced professional with a background in Customer Sales and Service, I possess a Master's degree in Applied Mathematics and comprehensive training in Data Science. My expertise lies in advanced programming, machine learning, and data visualization. Skilled in aggregating and analyzing datasets, I uncover valuable insights to enhance decision-making processes and identify key performance indicators.

SKILLS

DATA SCIENCE: Advanced data analysis, machine learning algorithms, predictive modeling, statistical analysis

OPERATIONS RESEARCH: Optimization, mathematical modeling, algorithm development

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Python, SQL

TOOLS AND LIBRARIES: TensorFlow, PyTorch, scikit-learn, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Tableau

DATA ANALYTICS: Data gathering, Data processing, Requirements specification, end-to-end analysis, Web scraping

EMPLOYMENT

SPRINGBOARD

New York Springboard Data Science Career Track - Student Mar. 2023 to Current

- Applied advanced data science techniques to analyze large datasets, driving cost reduction, increased profitability, and enhanced customer experience.
- Conducted research on industry trends and emerging opportunities to identify best practices and strategies for revenue growth.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to gather data requirements, conduct end-to-end analyses.
- Utilized operations research expertise to optimize processes, develop algorithms, and build mathematical models to address business challenges.
- Employed machine learning and artificial intelligence techniques for predictive modeling, anomaly detection, and optimization efforts.
- Successfully completed projects that led to improvements in operational efficiency, customer satisfaction, and revenue growth.
- Coordinating meetings and conference calls between data users and experts.
- Assist in organizing presentations.
- Continuously stayed abreast of the latest advancements and trends in the field of data science, incorporating new knowledge.

FEDEX

Inside Sales Support Specialist • Supervising queries from the trade partners.

New York Apr. 2022 to Mar. 2023

- Manage all gueries about new quotes and confirmations.
- Communicate with account managers, trade partners and other operational teams to resolve customers issues to meet and exceed our revenue
- Provide outstanding customer service by demonstrating responsiveness, communication, initiative, creativity, and willingness to go the extra mile.

EMIRATES AIRLINE

New york Sept. 2007 to Dec. 2021

Senior Groups Sales Agent

• Supervising queries from customers/travel agents about reservations, ticketing, and group fares.

- Internal and external communication with head office and local sales teams to meet and exceed sales target.
- Customer service regarding new promotions and benefits, support ongoing maintenance of local pricing fare structures, manage fare reviews.
- Prepare all reports for regional and head offices including market analysis, flown reporting, analysis, and reviews.
- Providing orientation and training for new employees of the sales department
- Handling of Emirates frequent Flyer loyalty Program, Sky wards.

PROJECTS

MACHINE LEARNING-DRIVEN HOUSE PRICE PREDICTION AND AFFORDABLE VALUE-BOOSTING RECOMMENDATIONS IN AMES, IOWA

Analyzed four models (RandomForestRegressor, LGBMRegressor, XGBRegressor, linearRegression) to predict house prices.

- XGBRegressor with GridSearch tuning performed the best (MAE: \$16,718, MAPE: 11%).
- Valuable insights for real estate analysis and decision-making; SHAP force plot visualizes feature impact on prices.